[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Metal Scraping ]
[ Swishing Sound ]
[ Panting ]
[ Thunderclaps ]
- [ Gasps ] - [ Thunderclaps ]
[ Horse Snorts ]
[ Metal Scraping ]
- [ Alarm Bell Ringing ] - [ Man ] Help here ! Lend a hand here !
- [ Ringing ] - Anyone .
Constable Crane .
Ichabod Crane ! Is that you ?
None other . Not only me .
I have found something .
which was lately a man .
- Burn it . - Yes , sir .
Just a moment . We do not yet know the cause of death .
When you find them in the river , cause of death is drowning .
Possibly so , if there is water in the lungs . But by pathology ,
we might be able to determine whether or not he was dead
before he went into the river .
I will need to examine the body .
Cut him up . Are we heathens ?
What happened to him ?
Nothing , sir . Arrested for burglary .
[ Screaming ]
- [ Trap Door Slams Shut ] - Good work .
[ Crane ] The millennium is almost upon us .
In a few months. we will be living in the 19th century .
Yet our courts continue to rely on medieval devices of torture .
- Stand down . - I stand up for sense and justice .
Our jails overflow with men and women convicted on confessions
. worth no more than this one . - Constable Crane .
This is a song we have heard from you more than once .
Now. there are two courses open to me .
First , I can let you cool your heels in the cells ...
until you learn respect for the dignity
. of my office . - I beg pardon .
But why am I the only one who sees that to solve crimes ... .
... to detect the guilty , we must use our brains
. to recognize vital clues ...
using up-to-date scientific techniques ?
Which brings me to the second course .
There is a town upstate , two days ' journey to the north ...
in the Hudson highlands .
It is a place called Sleepy Hollow .
Have you heard of it ?
I have not .
An isolated farming community , mainly Dutch .
Three persons have been murdered there , all within a fortnight .
Each one found with the head ... ..
... lopped off . - Lopped off ?
Clean as dandelion heads , apparently .
You will take these experimentations of yours to Sleepy Hollow ,
and there you will detect the murderer .
Bring him here to face our good justice .
Will you do this ?
I shall .
Remember , it is you ,
Ichabod Crane .
who is now put to the test .
[ Animal Howling ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Music ]
[ Excited Chattering ]
The Pickety Witch . The Pickety Witch .
Who 's got a kiss for the Pickety Witch ? The Pickety Witch .
The Pickety Witch . Who 's got a kiss for the Pickety Witch ?
Is it Theodore ?
Your pardon , miss . I am a stranger .
Then have a kiss on account .
I am looking for Baltus Van Tassel .
I am his daughter , Katrina Van Tassel .
And who are you , friend ? We have not heard your name yet .
I have not said it . Excuse me .
- You need some manners . - Brom .
Come , come . We will have no raised voices .
It is only to raise spirits during this dark time
that I and my dear wife are giving this little party .
Young sir , you are most welcome , even if you are selling something .
Thank you , sir .
I am Constable Ichabod Crane sent to you from New York
to investigate murder in Sleepy Hollow .
Then Sleepy Hollow is grateful to you , Constable Crane .
And we hope you will honor us by remaining in this house .
Well spoke , dear .
Come sir , we will get you settled . Play on .
[ Music Continues ]
Excuse me , please .
Thank you .
Please tell Mr. Van Tassel I will be down in a moment .
I will , sir .
Thank God you 're here .
[ Door Creaking ]
Ah , excellent . Come in .
Leave us. my dear .
We are joined by Dr. Thomas Lancaster ,
Reverend Steenwyck .
our able magistrate Samuel Philipse ,
and lastly , this fine fellow is James Hardenbrook ,
- our notary . - And you , sir ?
A simple farmer who has prospered .
The town looks to me as friend and counsel .
And landlord , and banker . Can we proceed ?
Thank you .
So
three persons murdered .
First , Peter Van Garrett ...
and his son , Dirk Van Garrett .
Both of them strong ,
capable men ,
found together ,
decapitated .
One week later , the Widow Winship .
Also ... decapitated .
Now , I will need to ask you many questions .
But first , let me ask :
Is anyone suspected ?
How much have your superiors explained to you , Constable ?
Only that the three were slain in open ground ,
their heads found severed from their bodies .
Hmm .
Their heads were not found severed . Their heads were not found at all .
- The heads are ... gone ? - Taken .
Taken by the Headless Horseman .
Taken back to Hell .
Pardon . I don 't - -
Perhaps you had better sit down .
Yes .
The Horseman was a Hessian mercenary ...
sent to these shores by German princes ...
to keep Americans under the yoke of England .
But unlike his compatriots who came for money ,
the Horseman came for love of carnage .
When battle was joined , there you 'd find him .
He rode agiant blacksteed named Dared evil .
Aah ! Aah !
He was infamous for riding his horse hard into battle .
chopping off heads at full gallop .
He had filed his teeth down to sharp points ...
to add to the ferocity of his appearance .
[ Snarling ]
[ Gunshot ]
This butcher didn 't finally reach his end until the winter of ' 79 .
not far from here in our Western Woods .
[ Gunshot ]
[ Gunshots Continue ]
- Shh . - [ Twig Snaps ]
[ Panting ]
They chopped off his head with his own sword .
Even today. the Western Woods is a haunted place ... ...
where brave men will not venture .
For what was planted in the ground that day ...
was a seed of evil .
[ Whinnying ]
And so it has been for 20 years .
But now the Hessian wakes .
He 's on the rampage . cutting off heads where he finds them .
Are you saying - - Is that what you believe ?
Seeing is believing .
They tell me you have brought books and trappings ...
of scientific investigation .
This is the only book I recommend you read .
[ Crane ] I see .
Reverend Steenwyck . Gentlemen .
Murder needs no ghosts to come from the grave .
We have murder sin in New York without benefit of ghouls and goblins .
You 're a long way from New York , Constable .
The assassin is a man of flesh and blood ,
and I will discover him .
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Bleating ]
Come out , devil .
[ Hoof beats Approaching ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Quacking ]
His name 's Gunpowder .
He should do just fine , Mr. Killian , Thank you .
Good luck , sir . If you need help , call my name .
Much appreciated .
Don 't you worry about a thing .
Everything 's going to be just fine .
Thomas ! Inside !
Run along for your breakfast .
Kiss your mother once for you and twice for me .
- [ Gunshot ] - Murder . The Horseman 's killed again .
All right , Gunpowder , we 're off .
Come on . No , no .
- Come on , the other way . Turn around . - Hyah .
Good horsie .
Mr. Miller ,
... . ride back for the coffin cart . - Yes , sir .
The rest of you , keep a sharp lookout .
It 's all right . I am here now .
The fourth victim , Jonathan Masbath .
I see .
And ... the head ?
Taken .
Interesting .
- Very interesting . - What is ?
In headless corpse cases of this sort ,
the head is removed to prevent identification of the body .
But we know this was Jonathan Masbath .
Precisely . So why was the head removed ?
- Why ? - Right .
- You have moved the body ? - I did .
- You must never move the body . - Why not ?
Because .
The stride is gigantic .
The attacker rode Masbath down ,
turned his horse .
Came back . Came back to claim the head .
[ Powder Sizzling ]
Yes . There 's a chemical reaction .
It shows there was a powerful , singular thrust to the neck .
Now .
[ Gasps ] Interesting .
What is it ?
The wound was cauterized in the very instant
as though the blade itself were red-hot .
And yet , no blistering , no scorched flesh .
The devil 's fire .
[ Reverend Steenwyck ] " Be vigilant . " as it sayeth in the Book of Peter .
Chapter 5 , Verse 8 .
" Because your adversary , the devil ,
" as a roaring lion , walketh about .
Seeking whom he may devour . "
God rest . Jonathan Masbath .
Mr. Constable , sir .
Ah . You 're young Masbath .
I was young Masbath , but now the only one .
Masbath , at your service .
In honor bound to avenge my father .
Well , one and only Masbath , I thank you very much ,
but your mother will need you more than I.
My mother is in Heaven , sir .
She has my father now to care for her .
But you have no one to serve you . I am your man , sir .
Yes , and a brave one too . But I cannot be the one to look after you .
I am sorry for your loss , young Mr. Masbath .
- Constable Crane . - Mr. Philipse .
Something you should know .
Jonathan Masbath was not the fourth victim , but the fifth .
- The fifth ? - Aye .
Five victims in four graves .
Young Masbath .
Find a place in the Van Tassel 's servants ' quarters . Wake me before dawn .
I hope you have a strong stomach .
Peter Van Garrett .
Dirk Van Garrett .
Jonathan Masbath .
Five victims , four graves .
The Widow Winship .
[ Groans ]
[ Crane ] Bring the widow in .
This is most irregular , Constable .
I should hope so , but in this case , necessary .
We need to operate immediately .
Operate ? She 's dead .
When we say " operate " we mean , of course , I will need the operating table .
Once more , the neck wound cauterized .
The ... sword thrust to the stomach , the same .
But to what purpose ?
To what is your purpose , is the question .
What manner of instruments are these ?
Some of my own design .
All right , then . Step outside , young Masbath .
Thank you very much for your help . Mr. Killian .
And if you don 't mind , Doctor .
My concentration suffers greatly when I am observed .
[ Indistinct Chattering ]
I am finished .
What , in the name of God , have you done to her ?
We are dealing with a madman .
What did you find out ?
The Widow Winship was with child .
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Hooves Clopping ] [ Horse Snorting ]
[ Frogs Croaking " Ichabod " ]
[ Croaking Continues ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Hooves Clopping ]
Who 's there ?
[ Whinnying ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Woman 's Voice ] Ichabod
Ichabod
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh . Pardon my intrusion .
- I saw a light . - It is no intrusion .
I come here to read when I am wakeful .
- To read books which you must hide ? - They were my mother 's books .
My father believes tales of romance ...
because the brain fever that killed my mother .
She died two years ago come mid-winter .
The nurse who cared for her during her sickness is now Lady Van Tassel .
There was something else too .
Why did no one think to mention
. that the Van Garretts are kin to the Van Tassels ?
Because there is hardly a household in Sleepy Hollow ...
that is not connected to every other by blood or marriage .
I see .
This land we 're looking at was Van Garrett land ,
given to my father when I was in swaddling clothes .
The Van Garretts were the richest family around these parts .
When my father brought us to Sleepy Hollow .
Van Garrett set him up with an acre and a broken-down cottage .
My father worked hard for his family . and prospered and built this house .
I owe my happiness to him .
I remember living poor in the cottage .
- Should I show you ? - Yes .
Take this . It is my gift for you .
No , I have no use for it .
Are you so certain of everything ?
It was your mother 's .
Keep it close to your heart . It is sure protection against harm .
Are you so certain of everything ?
These are strange , these markings . What are they ?
I have had them since I can remember .
I used to play by this hearth as a child .
It was my first drawing school , and my mother was my teacher .
Look .
See ? Carved into the fireback ?
The Archer . I 'd forgotten it .
This was from long before we lived here .
- Are you all right ? - Yes , thank you .
- [ Bird Chirping ] - A cardinal .
My favorite .
I 'd love to have a tame one , but I wouldn 't have the heart to cage him .
Well , then , I ... have something for you .
Cardinal on one side .
An empty cage . And now - -
You can do magic . Teach me .
It is no magic . It is what we call optics .
Separate pictures which become one in the spinning .
It is truth , but truth is not always appearance .
[ Inaudible Arguing ]
What are you running from , Magistrate Philipse ?
- Damn you , Crane . - You had a mind to help me ?
- Yes , and it 's put me in mortal dread - - - Of what ?
Of powers against which there is no defense . Come .
How did you know the Widow Winship was expecting a child ?
- She told me . - Then I deduce you are the father .
I am not the father .
Did she tell you the name of the child 's father ?
Yes , she did . She came to me ...
for advice as town magistrate to protect the rights of her child .
I was bound by my oath of office to keep the secret , but - -
- Do you believe the father killed her ? - The Horseman killed her .
How often do I have to tell you there is no Horseman .
Never was a Horseman , and never will be a Horseman .
What is that thing ?
My talisman . It protects me from the Horseman .
You , a magistrate and your head full of such nonsense .
- Tell me the name of ... .. - [ Sheep Bleating ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Thunderclaps ]
- [ Thunderclaps ] - [ Squeaking ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
Oh , my God !
[ Knocking ]
Constable Crane ? Constable Crane ?
Has he not come out at all ?
- It was a Headless Horseman . - You must not excite yourself .
- But it was a Headless Horseman . - Of course . That 's why you 're here .
No , you must believe me . It was a Horseman , a dead one . Headless .
- I know . - You don 't know . You were not there .
- It 's all true . - Of course it is . Everyone told you .
I ... saw him .
I suppose it 's back to the city , then .
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Gasps ]
All right , this time I will get to New York myself .
I won 't be fobbed off with an amateur deductor .
This time . it 's a magistrate that 's dead ... .
Gentlemen . I need able men to go with me into the Western Woods .
You ? We thought you 'd shot your bolt .
I have faced my fears ,
and come out determined to locate the Horseman 's grave .
In short , to pit myself against a murdering ghost .
Who 's with me ?
Me .
The Van Garretts . Widow Winship .
Your father Jonathan Masbath .
And now Philipse . Something must connect them .
Did your father have dealings with the Van Garretts ?
He worked for them . We lived in the coach house .
It 's nothing .
But there was something that happened one night a week before the murder .
An argument upstairs between father and son .
And my father was later sent for by Mr. Van Garrett .
An argument between father and son .
After which the elder Van Garrett sent for his servant Masbath .
- Listen . - I hear nothing .
Nor I. No birds .
No crickets . It 's all gone so quiet .
Quicken pace .
[ Door Creaking ]
Pardon our intrusion .
- But perhaps you could help us . - You 're from the hollow .
Yes , in a way .
I should like to say , I make no assumptions about your occupation .
Nor your ways , which , which - -
Which are nothing to me , whatever you are .
Each to his own .
Oh .
Do you know of the Horseman , ma 'am ?
- The Hessian ? - [ Makes Slicing Sound ]
That will be him , ma 'am .
You , come with me .
Go out child . Keep away .
Whatever you hear . keep away .
What might he hear that he must keep away from ?
He rides ... to the hollow and back .
I hear him , I smell the blood on him .
Do you ? Well ,
I am here to find him and make him stop .
[ Bat Chirping ]
You seek knowledge of the netherworld ? I can show you .
- What are you doing ? - [ Sniffing ] Don 't move or speak .
- When the other comes , I will hold him . - The other ?
Silence . [ Sniffing ] He comes now .
Madam ?
Madam , do you hear me ?
[ Growling ]
You seek the warrior bathed in blood . The Headless Horseman .
Follow the Indian trail to where the sun dies .
Follow it to the Tree of the Dead .
Climb down to the Horseman 's resting place .
- We 're leaving . - What happened ?
We 're leaving now .
We take the Indian trail to the Tree of the Dead .
- How will we recognize it ? - Without difficulty , I rather fear .
Then climb down to the Horseman 's resting place .
- His camp ? - His grave .
Stay here .
Halt and turn . I have a pistol aimed .
Katrina .
I might have killed you . Why have you come ?
Because no one else would go with you .
I am now twice the man .
It is your white magic .
Pardon my intrusion .
I think you 'd better come and look at this .
The Tree of the Dead .
Blood .
Stay where you are .
- What is it ? - Just stay where you are . Don 't move .
This tree is a gateway .
A gateway between two worlds .
This ground has been disturbed . The soil is loose .
Bring the shovel .
The skull is gone . Taken .
That is why the Horseman returns from the grave .
To take heads till his own is restored to him .
[ Thunderclaps ]
Ichabod ?
[ Whinnies ]
[ Whinnying ]
Hyah ! Hyah !
- [ Thunderclaps ] - [ Horse Whinnies ]
Split up . Glenn . Theodore .
Don 't pick your teeth . You will teach Thomas bad habits .
I am a bad habit . There 's nothing for it .
Oh , isn 't there ?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Wind Howling ]
- Come on , let 's get ready for bed . - Yes .
[ Thunderclaps ]
Beth , run .
Stay quiet .
- [ Panting , Gasps ] - [ Door Opens ]
- [ Beth Gasps ] - [ Sword Slashes ]
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Thomas Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Whinnying ]
- Wait ! He 's not after you . - I will get him .
We cannot win this .
[ Loud Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
Aah !
[ Thunderclaps ]
Remarkable . A wound like this should have killed him . But it needs no stitch ,
... . and there 's hardly a loss of blood . - [ Gasps ]
You must be still .
- The fever is on you . - Katrina .
Nostradamus , Mediamus , Milk of Mercy ,
in media noslaudamas .
Katrina , I tried to stop Brom , but - -
Shh . Drink this down . It will make you sleep .
The Horseman was not set to kill Brom or me . Had Brom not attacked him ... .
Later . Rest now .
I have discovered something . The Horseman does not kill at random .
His victims are chosen by someone who controls him .
By that very person who took his skull .
Someone who knew where to dig .
Someone of flesh and blood , as I have always said .
- These are ravings . - Shh . Drink .
[ Lady Crane 's Voice ] Ichabod .
[ Gasps ]
Shh . You were dreaming .
Yes . Things I had forgotten .
- And would not like to remember . - Tell me what you dreamt .
My mother was an innocent .
A child of nature .
Condemned .
Murdered ... by my father .
Murdered by ... .
Murdered to save her soul ...
by a Bible-black tyrant behind a mask of righteousness .
I was seven ... when I lost my faith .
What do you believe in ?
Sense and reason . Cause and consequence .
I should not have come to this place ...
where my rational mind has been so controverted by the spirit world .
Will you take nothing from Sleepy Hollow that was worth the coming here ?
No .
No , not nothing .
A kiss from a lovely young woman ...
before she saw my face or knew my name .
Yes , without sense or reason .
Forgive me , I speak of kisses ...
and you have lost your brave man , Brom .
I have shed my tears for Brom .
And yet my heart is not broken .
Do you think me wicked ?
No .
Perhaps there is a bit of a witch in you , Katrina .
Why do you say that ?
Because you have bewitched me .
Oh .
- You slept like the dead . - You 're too kind to me .
I do not look to be served by the lady of the house .
Nor would you be , but that the servant girl has vanished .
- Sarah ? - Run away like so many others .
They 're all leaving in fear .
Where is Katrina ?
She watched over you till dawn . Now it is her turn to sleep .
Well , I am fit for another day , I think .
Fit enough to face a mortal adversary .
Dr. Lancaster .
Reverend Steenwyck .
Hmm .
Notary Hardenbrook . And Magistrate Philipse .
Who tried to cut and run and lost his head .
All frightened men , arguing together
on the very night Magistrate Philipse was killed .
There is conspiracy here .
The doctor . The reverend . the notary and the magistrate .
What is this secret that unites them ?
Magistrate Philipse knew ...
there were five bodies to four graves .
He knew the widow was pregnant .
He could not tell me the name of the father .
What does this point to ?
We must proceed by a process of elimination .
I shall make a list of every man and woman in Sleepy Hollow ...
starting with its chief citizen . Baltus Van Tassel .
I feel we 're getting very close .
I suppose Baltus is the chief citizen now that old Van Garrett is dead .
Yes , the Van Garretts .
I 'd almost forgotten them .
Come with me .
- Where ? - To Notary Hardenbrook 's .
- Have you thought of something ? - Yes .
I have .
Hopeless .
My father 's satchel . Why is it here ?
[ Gasps ]
- Leave me alone . - Notary Hardenbrook .
Leave me alone .
As soon as you show me the last will and testament of old man Van Garrett .
The will leaves everything to his son .
Who died with him . So the estate passes to the next of kin .
Naturally . All legal and above board .
Sir ?
I am a dead man . No , no .
Van Garrett 's seal ... broken .
Seems Van Garrett made a new will just before he died .
Naming ...
Widow Winship ?
And here , look .
- A marriage certificate . - Aha !
Old Van Garrett secretly married the widow .
Left everything to her and her unborn child .
So the new will stood between the Van Garrett fortune
and the person who would have otherwise inherited everything .
It 's true . But we four were drawn in against our will !
- Your will ? - He means ... .
Of course . The four town elders .
Now I see what parts you had to play .
Reverend Steenwyck knew the secret because he performed the marriage .
Dr. Lancaster attended the pregnant woman .
Magistrate Philipse gave protection of the law .
And Notary Hardenbrook concealed the documents ...
which had been entrusted by Van Garrett to his faithful servant .
The four conspirators drawn into the plot .
We did not know it was a murdering plot .
But I have not finished , sir .
First , the Van Garretts , father and son , slain by a horseman ...
raised from the grave to chop heads .
Now , up pops a widow with a claim on the fortune . Off with her head .
But murder begets murder .
It was the servant , Jonathan Masbath .
The night father and son quarrelled over the new will ,
Jonathan Masbath was summoned upstairs to bear witness .
Here is his signature . I am afraid it was his death warrant , young Masbath .
The Horseman came for him .
Came for him at the bidding of someone who had power over him .
Someone who dug in the earth in the Western Woods and stole the skull .
The missing head which must be restored to the Horseman ...
before he will return to hell .
Someone who stood to gain or lose a fortune .
None other than Van Garrett 's next of kin .
Baltus Van Tassel .
Katrina ? Why are you in my room ?
Because it is yours .
Was it wicked of me ?
No , no , not at all .
I missed you . Where did you go ?
To the Notary . I had questions to ask Hardenbrook .
Did you learn anything of interest ?
Perhaps .
- My father ... . - Your father ?
Yes . My father thinks you should return to New York .
Really ? Why is that ?
I don 't know .
Perhaps he looked in your ledger and did not like what he saw .
- What have you there ? - Evidence . I am sorry , I must ask you ...
Then I will leave you to your thoughts .
[ Gasps ]
- It 's just a spider . - Kill it . Kill it .
No. no. stomp it !
- There 's something under here . - What is it ?
- Help me move the bed . - No , I mustn 't . You do it .
The evil eye . It is someone casting spells against you .
The evil eye ?
[ Thumping Sound ]
Wait here .
Katrina , you took the evidence and burned it .
So you would not have it to accuse my father .
I accuse no one . But if there is guilt ,
I cannot alter it no matter how much it grieves me .
And no spells of yours can alter it , either .
Your father has the motive . It is he who stands to profit from these murders .
If you knew him , you would not have such harsh thoughts about him .
Nor if you felt anything for me .
I am pinioned by a chain of reasoning .
Why else did his friends conspire to conceal ...
You are the constable . So find another chain of reasoning and let me be .
I cannot . Nor the one or the other . And I am heartsick with it .
I think you have no heart . And I had a mind once to give you mine .
Yes , I think you loved me that day
when you followed me into the Western Woods to have braved such peril .
What peril was there for me if it was my own father
who controlled the Headless Horseman ?
Good-bye , Ichabod Crane . I curse the day you came to Sleepy Hollow .
[ Whinnies ]
- She will not see you . - Did she say anything ?
[ Sighs ] Only that she will not come down .
I see . Thank you .
Constable ?
You have not asked me how I have hurt my hand since yesterday ,
which would have been polite .
In fact , you have been as careful ...
not to look at it as not to mention it .
Yes . I am sorry . How did you ... .
- I know you saw me . - What ?
I know you followed last night ,
and you must promise not to tell my husband what you saw .
Promise me .
The town is in ferment .
Horror piled on tragedy . Hardenbrook is dead .
- Oh , no . That harmless old man ? - Hanged himself in the night .
Hanged himself ?
Reverend Steenwyck 's called a meeting in the church tonight .
Every man , woman and child is going to speak out against you .
If you are wise . you will leave this place .
What is that ?
I was careless with the kitchen knife .
[ Baltus ] The wound looks angry .
I will bind it later with wild-arrow root flowers .
I know where some grow .
[ Church Bell Ringing ]
[ Humming ]
Come on , hurry up .
The meeting bell started to ring .
[ Thunderclaps ]
[ Bell Ringing ]
The Horseman .
- Katrina . The Horseman saved me . - Father ?
He killed her . The Horseman killed your stepmother .
- [ Thunderclaps ] - [ Horse Whinnying ]
Oh , God !
[ Man ] Fire !
[ Whinnying ]
[ Shouting , Screaming ]
You will kill us all . You 're the one the Horseman wants .
He cannot enter .
- The Horseman cannot enter . - Why should we die for you ?
The Horseman cannot enter . He cannot cross the gate .
We have to save ourselves .
The next person that lays a hand on me will get a bullet .
He 's coming back .
[ Whinnies ]
Enough have died already . It 's time to confess our sins .
- What is it that you know ? - Your four friends played you false .
We were devilishly possessed by one who ... .
- [ Gunshot ] - [ Gasps ]
Get out of my way ! Stand back ! Stay back !
Back ! Stand back .
There is a conspiracy here , and I will shake it out .
[ Screams ]
It was an evil spirit possessed you .
I pray God it is satisfied now , and that you find peace .
The evil eye 's done its work .
My life is over , spared for a lifetime of horrors in my sleep ,
waking each day to grief .
Good-bye , Katrina .
[ Hoof beats ]
Whoa .
You think it was Katrina , don 't you ?
That can never be uttered .
A strange sort of witch , with a kind and loving heart .
- How can you think so ? - I have good reason .
- Then you are bewitched by reason . - I am beaten down by it .
It is a hard lesson for a hard world , and you had better learn it .
Villainy wears many masks . None so dangerous as the mask of virtue .
Farewell .
- Return the coach . Turn around now . - What ?
Whoa .
[ Knocking ]
Pardon my intrusion .
No blood flow , no clotting , no healing .
When this cut was made , this woman was already dead .
Dear stepdaughter .
You look as if you 'd seen a ghost .
Yah !
Rise up once more , my Dark Avenger .
One more night of beheading .
Rise up with your sword .
A head ... for a head .
My unholy Horseman , rise .
[ Lady Van Tassel ] Come now for ... Katrina .
[ Whinnying ]
Awake at last .
Did you think it was all a nasty dream ?
Father saw the Horseman kill you .
He saw the Horseman come towards me with his sword unsheathed ,
but it is I who govern the Horseman , my dear .
and Baltus did not stay to watch .
Yah ! Yah !
- But there was a body . - The servant girl , Sarah .
[ Lady Van Tassel 's Voice ] And I always thought she was useless .
But it seems she had a purpose after all .
Who are you ?
My family name was Archer .
The Archer .
[ Whinnying ]
I lived with my father and mother and sister in a cottage not far from here .
Until one day my father died . The landlord ,
who had received many years of loyal service from my parents , evicted us .
No one in this God-fearing town ...
would take us in because my mother was suspected of witchcraft .
But she schooled her daughters well ...
while we lived as outcasts in the Western Woods .
She died within a year .
My sister and I remained in our refuge ,
seeing not a soul .
Until one day , whilst gathering firewood ,
we crossed the path of the Hessian .
- Shh . - [ Twig Snaps ]
I saw his death .
At that moment , I offered my soul to Satan ...
if he would raise the Hessian from the grave to avenge me .
- Avenge you ? - Against Van Garrett .
The landlord who showed us no mercy and left us to starve , whilst ...
Baltus Van Tassel and his simpering wife and girl child stole our home .
I swore I would make myself mistress of all he had .
The easiest part was the first .
To enter your house as your mother 's sicknurse .
and put her body into the grave and my own into the marriage bed .
Not quite so easy was to secure my legacy .
The widow had to go , of course ,
and the servant Masbath .
And just the other day , that silly midwife , Killian ,
told me the widow had told her a big secret .
And she told me this right in front of her husband .
What a goose .
So. another little job for the Horseman .
But lust delivered the Reverend Steenwyck into my power .
Fear did the same for the Notary Hardenbrook ...
and the drunkard Philipse .
And the doctor 's silence I exchanged ...
for my complicity in his fornications with the servant girl . Sarah .
Yes , you have everything now .
No . You have , my dear , by your father 's will .
I get everything in the event of your death .
Oh. my sister. by the way .
sadly passed away ...
quite recently .
[ Katrina ] You killed your own sister ?
She brought it on herself by helping you and your master .
[ Laughing ] You 're just in time to have your head cut off .
The Horseman comes , and tonight he comes for you .
Katrina .
- Thank God . - [ Horse Whinnying ]
Watch your head .
To the roof ! I have an idea .
Jump for the sails .
[ Crane ] Jump .
Hurry .
- Is he dead ? - That 's the problem .
He was dead to begin with .
Hyah .
[ Horse Whinnies ]
- Where are we going ? - Anywhere but here .
Here . Take the reins .
[ Gunshot ]
Ichabod .
Yah !
My bag .
Jump .
[ Whinnying ]
Still alive ?
Run , Katrina .
Yes , do run , and jump , and skip .
- No ! - [ Gasps ]
[ Thunderclaps ]
Here . Take her .
She 's yours .
Sir , you 're not dead .
[ Screams ]
Horseman .
[ Whinnies ]
Hyah !
[ Gasps ]
[ Whinnies ]
Ahh . Just in time for a new century .
You will soon get your bearings , young Masbath .
The Bronx is up , the Battery 's down .
And home is this way .